### JAVIER LÓPEZ LORENZO

18 Pollard Close E16 1LG, London UK. Tel: +447449842958 Email: <u>illlorenzo@gmail.com</u>

#### **PROFILE**

Geotechnical & Surveying Engineer with over 4 years of experience in various civil engineering projects of small and large scale in different countries such as Spain, Portugal and The UK.

Responsible and committed, easy to absorb new knowledge. I enjoy teamwork and I adapt to it quickly.

My objective is to apply and develop my knowledge in the field of Civil Engineering and thereby assist the company to achieve its objectives and goals, as well as acquire all the new knowledge and skills my job offers me.

#### **SKILLS**

IT Skills Full Domain Microsoft Office package (Access, Excel, Power Point,

Word).

Specific softwares Autocad 2D/3D, MDT, Amberg Tunnel, TMS Office, Slope Stability,

ArcGis 10.

Languages Spanish - Native

English - Full professional competence

#### **CAREER HISTORY**

# JAVINK ENGINEERING SERVICES LIMITED Currently

Freelance Engineering Surveyor at BBMV c510 - Crossrail

#### INTERGEO INVESTMENT UK 2013 - 2014

#### Monitoring Surveyor at *The Crossrail* running tunnels in the following matters:

- providing settlement data to be used by the tunnelling contractor for the purpose of assisting a review of working methods, thus avoiding damage to structures and services.
- Monitoring the continuous SCL (Sprayed Concrete Lining) site activities at the tunnel face and the execution of other works in order to produce an end product that meets the design intent.
- Using data capture from robotic total stations, Digital Levels, inclinometers, extensometers, piezomters and crackmeters.

### INTERNACIONAL SECONDARY SCHOOL "NUEVO CENTRO" 2011-2012

#### IT & Mathematics Teacher, responsible for:

- Organization, maintenance and management of class systems in proper working condition.
- Design and development of appropriate computer instructional material.
- Development and implementation of lessons plans and classroom activities in consistent with the student management issues.
- theoretical and practical teaching of mathematics.

### LMR-DRILLING GmbH 2007-2009

#### Technical Sales Engineer in The Iberian Peninsula, in the following matters:

- Creating a database of major construction engineering of the Iberian Peninsula.
- Identifying major works that required the use of our techniques.
- visiting potential customers and budgeting for their works.
- Coordinating field work and mediate between German workers and the client.

## EMPRESARIOS AGRUPADOS AIE 2006-2007

#### Student Intern for the Civil Department, colaborating on:

- Interpretation and preparation of geotechnical reports.
- Design and calculation of shallow and deep foundations.
- Study of the seismic amplifications of various areas according to their parameters using specific softwares.

### **EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS**

2010 – 2011 UNIVERSIDAD COMPLUTENSE DE MADRID

Master's degree in education training for professional, secondary, and

language teachers.

2000 – 2007 UNIVERSIDAD POLITÉCNICA DE MADRID

Bachelor's degree in Geological & Geotechnical Engineering. (\*)

(\*) Final Project title: "Geotechnical design and economical viability for a hotel construction in San Roque (Cadiz, Spain)".

#### **COURSES/CERTIFICATES**

- Smartcard scheme for Construction and Engineering workers on London Underground (LUCAS).
- Personal Track Safety (PTS).
- CSCS For Managers and professionals.

#### **REFERENCES**

Available on request.